<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Links on Nathan Lane</title>
    <link>http://nathanlane.github.io/tags/links/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Links on Nathan Lane</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 01:10:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://nathanlane.github.io/tags/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On developmentalism, planning, &amp; early big data in Allende&#39;s Chile.</title>
      <link>http://nathanlane.github.io/posts/2014-10-09-developmentalism-planning-and-early-big-data-in-allendes-chile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 01:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nathanlane.github.io/posts/2014-10-09-developmentalism-planning-and-early-big-data-in-allendes-chile/</guid>
      <description>&#34;In Allende’s Chile, a futuristic op room was to bring socialism into the computer age.&#34;
Link: From the New Yorker - `The Planning Machine&#39; By Evgeny Morozov ``The consultant, Stafford Beer, had been brought in by Chile’s top planners to help guide the country down what Salvador Allende, its democratically elected Marxist leader, was calling `the Chilean road to socialism.&#39; Beer was a leading theorist of cybernetics—a discipline born of midcentury efforts to understand the role of communication in controlling social, biological, and technical systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A great primer on cleaning OCRd data with Python &amp; Regular Expressions.</title>
      <link>http://nathanlane.github.io/posts/2014-09-03-a-great-primer-of-cleaning-ocrd-data-with-python-regular-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 06:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nathanlane.github.io/posts/2014-09-03-a-great-primer-of-cleaning-ocrd-data-with-python-regular-expressions/</guid>
      <description>Link: Cleaning OCR’d text with Regular Expressions Often the pain of optical character recognition isn&#39;t the OCRing procedure itself, it is cleaning the tiny, little inconsistencies that plague OCRd content. This is especially true when we OCR historical material: even high quality scans can have a speckle or two that get recognized as gibberish.
Adept use of Regular Expressions (regex) coupled with simple Python (or Ruby scripts--or heck, even Notepad++) can be a powerful means of removing nasty errors from OCRd text/CSV files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The data on white anxiety over Hispanic immigration</title>
      <link>http://nathanlane.github.io/posts/2014-08-15-the-data-on-white-anxiety-over-hispanic-immigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nathanlane.github.io/posts/2014-08-15-the-data-on-white-anxiety-over-hispanic-immigration/</guid>
      <description>The data on white anxiety over Hispanic immigration (Via my pal, UMass Prof. Arin Dube)
A fantastic piece on racial anxiety and views on race. A nice little combination of academic research and polling insights. 
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historic Aggregate Data for Korea, 1910-1945 -- and beyond.</title>
      <link>http://nathanlane.github.io/posts/2014-08-15-historic-aggregate-data-for-korea-1910-1945-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 02:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nathanlane.github.io/posts/2014-08-15-historic-aggregate-data-for-korea-1910-1945-and/</guid>
      <description>Historic Aggregate Data for Korea, 1910-1945 -- and beyond. Here is a cool batch of datasets (mainly aggregates!) from Korea&amp;#8217;s Nakseongdae Institute of Economic Research, one of which is a nice collection of material covering the colonial Japanese period of Korea (1910-1945). [Just run that sucker through Google translate.]
If you&amp;#8217;re doing data work in economic history, your life is messy. Even more, if you&amp;#8217;re doing historical work for a developing country, finding the data is often a massive part of the job.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>