<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Nathan Lane, PhD</title>
    <link>http://example.com/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Nathan Lane, PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.com/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial: R Code Style for Empirical Economists</title>
      <link>http://example.com/post/2015-12-20-tutorial-r-code-style-for-empirical-economists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/post/2015-12-20-tutorial-r-code-style-for-empirical-economists/</guid>
      <description>Make your code understandable. IBM&#39;s data center in the 1960s, Toronto. Source:ibm-1401.info/ Heuristics, Hunches, &amp;amp; Why the Heck We Care. We hear many horror stories about big names having their results over turned over because of problems in our code. The struggle is real.
With this in mind, even simple rules of thumb used in programming can have large payoffs for social scientists. Especially since best practices are never discussed in graduate coursework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Data in R</title>
      <link>http://example.com/post/2015-10-18-taking-geospatial-data-to-r-how-to-ditch-arcgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/post/2015-10-18-taking-geospatial-data-to-r-how-to-ditch-arcgis/</guid>
      <description>Taking Geospatial Data to R (&amp; how to ditch ArcGIS) For R users it&#39;s very straightforward to ditch ArcGIS (for most tasks) in favor of doing everything through an R script. There are many reasons to do this:
 First, if you can do GIS work on your Linux system or Mac without having to run things through a lame emulator. Second, you can cut yourself loose from dealing with the clunky ArcGIS licensing system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial: Growing Datasets in R</title>
      <link>http://example.com/post/2015-06-26-quick-note-growing-datasets-more-efficiently-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 11:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.com/post/2015-06-26-quick-note-growing-datasets-more-efficiently-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Figure: From the Field Museum archives, 1920, Photographer Herbert P. Burtch, Oriental Institute. &#34;Men moving Totem Pole outside Field Museum by train.&#34;
Note: This was originally some notes to RAs but I figured it may be useful for other people out there.
I&#39;ve had some discussion with econ folks and RAs who are working with giant datasets in R for the first time. In particular, those having to &#34;harvest&#34; or &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>